So onto our approach, our divergence of choice is the reverse KL whose minimization may be viewed as an RL problem with rewards being the log distribution ratios.
Thus, given any estimate of the ratio, any RL algorithm can be used for solving the IL objective.
So a naive approach would be to train two density estimators, say flows independently.
Practically, this means alternating between learning them and using their log ratio as reward.
This fails when tried.
We'll see this again in the ablation.
And the failure can be further understood through what we term the BC graphs corresponding to an estimator for the log-distribution ratio.
The full description is in the paper, but intuitively, a lack of an upward trend implies failure in RL, which is precisely what occurs in the figure for the independent flows.
This connection is also formalized in the paper.
What we have here is a problem of out-of-distribution data.
The flow's values are meaningless when evaluated on each other's data.
We need to couple them somehow.
They must be coupled.