So first, let's talk about our motivation.
As many previous works have pointed out, misinformation campaigns are manipulating public opinions on hotspot topics, such as COVID-19 epidemic and vaccines.
For example, a publication pointed out that in those places where misinformation from misinformation campaigns spreads faster, the vaccination rate in these places is also higher.
relatively lower than other places.
So, to design mitigation strategies to reduce user susceptibility to misinformation, we need to understand how misinformation influences user beliefs and activities.
However, most of the existing works suffers from one or more of the following limitations.
So first, almost all the data-driven methodologies or data-driven analysis focus on correlation between misinformation and user activities.
And it is well known that causality is different from correlation.
So they cannot distinguish causal effect of misinformation from user prior beliefs.
Let us use the case of misinformation and the vaccine ratio.
One explanation could be that in this place, people primarily do not trust vaccines, so they do not take vaccines and they spread a lot of misinformation.
That could be true, but the correlation analysis cannot help us distinguish causality.
And there are some other works trying to understand the real causal effect.
But they mainly rely on random controlled experiments and surveys.
So, first, they are very costly.
And secondly, they may bring some ethical risk if we apply them on very large social media platforms.