We collect COVID-19 related tweets ranging from February 1, 2020 to September 30, 2021.
For data pre-processing, we first remove non-English tweets and retweets.
Then we filter out the tweets containing URLs.
Afterwards, we use a list of symptoms as keywords to match the tweets to extract medical-related tweets.
Finally, 10,000 tweets are annotated.
Among them, 6000 are randomly sampled, and the other 4000 are from the model labeled data.
All of them are manually checked.
We define seven entity types based on public health research needs.
including three general entity types and four medical entity types for annotation.
In particular, we select four entity types for additional sentiment annotation with three types of sentiment labels, positive, negative, neutral.